<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>loyalty on the crab &amp; musket</title><link>/tags/loyalty/</link><description>Recent content in loyalty on the crab &amp; musket</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/loyalty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Loyalty: a primer for my friends and family</title><link>/blog/loyalty-a-primer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/loyalty-a-primer/</guid><description>Loyalty is not a cool idea. Its image has been tarnished by consumer loyalty programs and the party loyalty of partisan politics. But a hundred years ago, American philosopher Josiah Royce had a unique, hopeful vision of loyalty which defied its poor (even back then) reputation. I was enthralled by his ideas, because they seemed utterly relevant to life today&amp;mdash;both to the big debates of the intelligentsia, and also to the choices myself and my friends are making for ourselves.</description></item><item><title>Loyalty: a primer for my friends and family</title><link>/drafts/loyalty-a-primer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/drafts/loyalty-a-primer/</guid><description>Loyalty is not a cool idea. Its image has been tarnished by consumer loyalty programs and the party loyalty of partisan politics. But a hundred years ago, American philosopher Josiah Royce had a unique, hopeful vision of loyalty which defied its poor (even back then) reputation. I was enthralled by his ideas, because they seemed utterly relevant to life today&amp;mdash;both to the big debates of the intelligentsia, and also to the choices myself and my friends are making for ourselves.</description></item><item><title>Loyalty and the Grand Philosophical Exception</title><link>/drafts/the-rehabilitation-of-loyalty/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/drafts/the-rehabilitation-of-loyalty/</guid><description>The word &amp;ldquo;loyalty&amp;rdquo; makes me think of flimsy punch-cards printed with arrays of takeaway coffees or Subway sandwiches. It reminds me of the soldiers of World War I, naïvely believing in something more than the cynical game of geopolitics. It describes simple-minded faithful canines, and those who toe the party line.
Even a hundred years ago, loyalty had a poor reputation. In 1907, Josiah Royce set out to rehabilitate the idea of loyalty from its unsavoury historical baggage.</description></item><item><title>Loyalty: A Primer For My Friends and Family</title><link>/drafts/loyalty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/drafts/loyalty/</guid><description>Loyalty is a bit of a dirty word. It&amp;rsquo;s been associated with so many unpleasant ideas, actions, and movements that it&amp;rsquo;s hard for us to overcome its nauseating baggage. When loyalty is mentioned, we are more likely to remember the Nuremberg trials than the civil rights movement. We&amp;rsquo;re more likely to imagine lackeys and lickspittles than we are heroes &amp;ndash; and even our images of loyal heroes are likely to be re-examined through lenses that reveal their privilege, supremacy and appropriation.</description></item></channel></rss>