<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>torque jams on the crab &amp; musket</title><link>/tags/torque-jams/</link><description>Recent content in torque jams on the crab &amp; musket</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/torque-jams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monster Mash: entry #2</title><link>/blog/monster-mash-entry-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/monster-mash-entry-2/</guid><description>Welcome one, welcome all to my third and final Monster Mash jam log. (Here&amp;rsquo;s the first one and the second.) Since I got busy during the week, this will basically summarise everything I did between Wednesday and the end of the jam last night. I&amp;rsquo;ll also write a bit of a post-mortem about the project and how I felt it went.
I have to report, unfortunately, that I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually make it into the jam, because a midnight I was fiddling with getting the game&amp;rsquo;s itch.</description></item><item><title>Monster Mash: entry #1</title><link>/blog/monster-mash-entry-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/monster-mash-entry-1/</guid><description>Welcome one, welcome all to my second Monster Mash jam log. (Here&amp;rsquo;s the first one.) I&amp;rsquo;ve got two days to summarise, since I didn&amp;rsquo;t do an awful lot of work yesterday. But, I:
Made a third-person camera controller with relative movement to the camera, all in script! This is an ugly hack and one I don&amp;rsquo;t want to repeat. The main challenge was the maths involved in converting the local direction we want to travel (e.</description></item><item><title>Monster Mash: entry #0</title><link>/blog/monster-mash-entry-0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/monster-mash-entry-0/</guid><description>The first day of my Monster Mash attempt has ended with some fortunate progress. Though I&amp;rsquo;m technically cheating (the jam starts tomorrow), I absolve myself by pointing out that I&amp;rsquo;ll be having a fairly busy week with several days off anyway - and I won&amp;rsquo;t be actually submitting the game, most likely. Since I had some time today while travelling, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d get some progress in early. I&amp;rsquo;m using Torque 3D and Blender for everything.</description></item></channel></rss>